<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Bettamind</string>
    <string name="phase_two_status">Fondation de design et de localisation</string>
    <string name="destination_today">Aujourd'hui</string>
    <string name="destination_today_description">Un point d'entree local quotidien apparaitra ici dans une phase ulterieure.</string>
    <string name="destination_reflect">Reflechir</string>
    <string name="destination_reflect_description">Un espace prive de reflection apparaitra ici dans une phase ulterieure.</string>
    <string name="destination_grow">Grandir</string>
    <string name="destination_grow_description">Des outils de croissance guides apparaitront ici dans une phase ulterieure.</string>
    <string name="destination_support">Soutien</string>
    <string name="destination_support_description">Local support actions and resources stay voluntary and private.</string>
    <string name="destination_settings">Reglages</string>
    <string name="destination_settings_description">Ajuster les fondations d'affichage de la phase 2.</string>
    <string name="placeholder_status">Espace reserve seulement. Aucun compte, synchronisation, IA ou moteur de stockage n'est actif.</string>
    <string name="settings_theme_title">Theme</string>
    <string name="settings_theme_light">Clair</string>
    <string name="settings_theme_dark">Sombre</string>
    <string name="settings_theme_calm">Calme</string>
    <string name="settings_theme_high_contrast">Contraste eleve</string>
    <string name="settings_font_title">Police lisible</string>
    <string name="settings_font_default">Noto Sans avec polices de secours par script</string>
    <string name="settings_font_accessible">Atkinson Hyperlegible avec polices de secours Noto</string>
    <string name="settings_locale_note">Les packs de langue sont des fondations brouillons en attente de revision avant utilisation en production.</string>
    <string name="phase_four_status">Deterministic growth workflow</string>
    <string name="phase_six_six_status">Deterministic daily tools foundation</string>
    <string name="daily_tools_title">Daily tools</string>
    <string name="daily_tools_description">Local check-ins, breathing, reminders, calendar entries and worksheets are deterministic and do not require AI, account access or backend services.</string>
    <string name="daily_checkin_title">Daily check-in</string>
    <string name="daily_checkin_description">Mood, energy, stress and sleep records use encrypted local storage only.</string>
    <string name="daily_breathing_title">Breathing and grounding</string>
    <string name="daily_breathing_description">Box breathing and grounding steps are fixed local exercises.</string>
    <string name="daily_breathing_pattern">One breathing cycle is %1$d seconds.</string>
    <string name="daily_reminder_title">Private reminders</string>
    <string name="daily_reminder_description">Reminders are local, optional and paused during quiet hours or pause-all.</string>
    <string name="daily_reminder_neutral_preview">Bettamind has a private reminder.</string>
    <string name="daily_calendar_title">Private calendar</string>
    <string name="daily_calendar_description">In-app entries stay private. System calendar handoff requires explicit approval and does not read the calendar.</string>
    <string name="daily_worksheet_title">Decision worksheets</string>
    <string name="daily_worksheet_description">Values-to-action, problem-solving, repair and difficult-conversation prompts are deterministic templates.</string>
    <string name="daily_record_storage_note">There is no unencrypted fallback, cloud sync, public ranking, streak or human-worth score.</string>
    <string name="ai_growth_modes_title">AI-assisted growth modes</string>
    <string name="ai_growth_modes_description">Quick Guidance, Guided Reflection, Deep Exploration and Action-Only can use a local model when available, but every mode keeps a deterministic no-model path.</string>
    <string name="ai_growth_quick_guidance_title">Quick Guidance</string>
    <string name="ai_growth_quick_guidance_description">Offers a short next-step frame after safety and boundary checks.</string>
    <string name="ai_growth_guided_reflection_title">Guided Reflection</string>
    <string name="ai_growth_guided_reflection_description">Helps organise awareness, choice and consequence without claiming therapy or diagnosis.</string>
    <string name="ai_growth_deep_exploration_title">Deep Exploration</string>
    <string name="ai_growth_deep_exploration_description">Looks for values, patterns and repair paths when a local model is available and safe to use.</string>
    <string name="ai_growth_action_only_title">Action-Only</string>
    <string name="ai_growth_action_only_description">Keeps the response focused on one practical action and avoids extended interpretation.</string>
    <string name="ai_growth_no_model_note">No model is required. If a local model is unavailable, Bettamind uses deterministic fallback keys.</string>
    <string name="ai_growth_safety_note">Relational and harm-safety checks run before generation and after generated output.</string>
    <string name="ai_growth_privacy_note">Daily context is used only after explicit consent, and sensitive AI context requires local step-up authentication.</string>
    <string name="growth_age_gate_title">Adult access</string>
    <string name="growth_age_gate_description">Personal growth features need local adult confirmation before use.</string>
    <string name="growth_age_confirm_adult">I am 18 or older</string>
    <string name="growth_age_not_adult">Not 18 or not sure</string>
    <string name="growth_age_adult_ready">Adult status is confirmed locally for this session.</string>
    <string name="growth_age_blocked">Adult personal features stay locked.</string>
    <string name="growth_storage_title">Narrative storage</string>
    <string name="growth_storage_locked">Storage remains off until adult access is confirmed.</string>
    <string name="growth_storage_unavailable">Persistent narrative storage is off until encrypted storage is available on this device.</string>
    <string name="growth_storage_ready">Encrypted narrative storage is available.</string>
    <string name="growth_today_title">Today flow</string>
    <string name="growth_step_locked">Confirm adult access to use the deterministic flow.</string>
    <string name="growth_step_complete_button">Mark step complete</string>
    <string name="growth_step_finished">Flow complete</string>
    <string name="growth_reset_session">Reset</string>
    <string name="growth_step_completed_label">Done</string>
    <string name="growth_reflect_title">Flow map</string>
    <string name="growth_reflect_description">The deterministic sequence stays the same without AI, backend or account access.</string>
    <string name="growth_summary_title">Growth summary</string>
    <string name="growth_summary_locked">Confirm adult access before starting personal growth features.</string>
    <string name="growth_summary_in_progress">Continue the current deterministic flow.</string>
    <string name="growth_summary_complete">This local flow is complete for now.</string>
    <string name="growth_summary_count">%1$d of %2$d steps completed</string>
    <string name="growth_support_title">Support boundary</string>
    <string name="growth_support_description">Support planning remains user-controlled. Bettamind does not contact anyone automatically.</string>
    <string name="growth_step_awareness">Awareness</string>
    <string name="growth_step_awareness_description">Name what is happening before choosing a response.</string>
    <string name="growth_step_choice">Choice</string>
    <string name="growth_step_choice_description">Identify the next deliberate choice.</string>
    <string name="growth_step_action">Action</string>
    <string name="growth_step_action_description">Choose one concrete action you can take.</string>
    <string name="growth_step_consequence">Consequence</string>
    <string name="growth_step_consequence_description">Consider likely effects without scoring personal worth.</string>
    <string name="growth_step_reflection">Reflection</string>
    <string name="growth_step_reflection_description">Review what the action revealed.</string>
    <string name="growth_step_repair">Repair</string>
    <string name="growth_step_repair_description">Notice whether repair is needed and what would be respectful.</string>
    <string name="growth_step_growth">Growth</string>
    <string name="growth_step_growth_description">Carry forward one lesson for the next choice.</string>
    <string name="privacy_lock_title">Privacy lock</string>
    <string name="privacy_lock_description">Bettamind can require local authentication before private encrypted storage is released. The recommended default is one minute.</string>
    <string name="privacy_lock_current_timeout">Current timeout: %1$s</string>
    <string name="privacy_lock_timeout_immediate">Immediate</string>
    <string name="privacy_lock_timeout_one_minute">One minute</string>
    <string name="privacy_lock_timeout_five_minutes">Five minutes</string>
    <string name="privacy_lock_timeout_fifteen_minutes">Fifteen minutes</string>
    <string name="privacy_lock_timeout_disabled">Disabled</string>
    <string name="privacy_lock_reauth_note">Reauthentication is still required before export, sync, professional sharing, recovery data, security changes, PIN changes, deleting local data or highly sensitive records.</string>
    <string name="privacy_lock_urgent_support">A locked screen may offer static urgent-support information without revealing personal data.</string>
    <string name="privacy_lock_notification_neutral">Bettamind has a private reminder.</string>
    <string name="relational_boundary_title">Relationship boundaries</string>
    <string name="relational_boundary_description">Bettamind can support human relationships, dating, consent and loneliness, but it is software, not a romantic or sexual partner.</string>
    <string name="relational_boundary_memory_note">Romantic, sexual, exclusivity or dependency signals are not eligible for permanent memory by default.</string>
    <string name="relational_boundary_notification_note">Reminder copy stays neutral and cannot imply Bettamind misses, needs or chooses the user.</string>
    <string name="phase_six_seven_status">Harmful-intent safeguards foundation</string>
    <string name="phase_seven_status">Optional AI growth modes foundation</string>
    <string name="harm_safety_title">Harm safety</string>
    <string name="harm_safety_description">Bettamind uses deterministic safeguards before and after AI so unsafe requests can be redirected without shame.</string>
    <string name="harm_safety_capability_note">Actionable harmful details are refused, while high-level prevention, emergency response, grounding and nonviolent repair remain available.</string>
    <string name="harm_safety_privacy_note">Sensitive safety content is excluded from memory, export, sync and notifications by default; sharing requires explicit preview and local authentication.</string>
    <string name="phase_nine_status">Optional encrypted export and sync foundation</string>
    <string name="encrypted_sync_title">Encrypted export and sync</string>
    <string name="encrypted_sync_description">Export, backup, device revocation and backend sync are optional. Sync is off by default and core use does not require an account or backend.</string>
    <string name="encrypted_sync_default_note">Bettamind prepares only encrypted, versioned, checksum-verified packages after explicit approval and local authentication.</string>
    <string name="encrypted_sync_privacy_note">Daily, relationship-boundary and harm-safety content is excluded by default; sensitive inclusion needs explicit selection and preview.</string>
    <string name="encrypted_sync_calendar_note">System-calendar handoff remains local and explicit, without broad calendar reading.</string>
    <string name="phase_ten_status">Global localisation and accessibility foundation</string>
    <string name="phase_eleven_status">Optional offline speech foundation</string>
    <string name="offline_speech_title">Offline speech</string>
    <string name="offline_speech_description">Speech input and output are optional. The text-only app remains complete without microphone access, speech packs or backend services.</string>
    <string name="offline_speech_text_fallback_title">Text-only fallback</string>
    <string name="offline_speech_text_fallback_body">All growth, daily, support and safety flows continue to work through text when speech is off or unavailable.</string>
    <string name="offline_speech_microphone_title">Microphone permission</string>
    <string name="offline_speech_microphone_body">Voice input requires explicit microphone permission. Bettamind does not listen passively.</string>
    <string name="offline_speech_audio_retention_title">No raw audio retention</string>
    <string name="offline_speech_audio_retention_body">Raw audio is not retained by default; sensitive transcripts require local app-lock protection.</string>
    <string name="offline_speech_packs_title">Speech packs</string>
    <string name="offline_speech_packs_body">OS offline voices are preferred. Any local speech pack must be licensed, signed, checksum-verified, removable and user-approved.</string>
    <string name="offline_speech_safety_note">Spoken input and output use the same relational-boundary and harm-safety pipeline as text, and voice output cannot be romantic, seductive, possessive or manipulative.</string>
    <string name="accessibility_title">Accessibility</string>
    <string name="accessibility_description">Screen-reader labels, large text, reduced motion, script fallbacks and simple wording are validated for the current foundation.</string>
    <string name="accessibility_reduced_motion_title">Reduced motion</string>
    <string name="accessibility_reduced_motion_description">Timers, transitions and grounding steps use static step-by-step presentation when reduced motion is on.</string>
    <string name="accessibility_low_literacy_title">Simple wording</string>
    <string name="accessibility_low_literacy_description">Use shorter, plain-language copy where an approved simple version is available.</string>
    <string name="accessibility_review_note">Safety, crisis, legal, privacy and consent translations stay blocked from production until qualified human review is recorded.</string>
    <string name="accessibility_toggle_on">On</string>
    <string name="accessibility_toggle_off">Off</string>
    <string name="phase_seven_five_status">Compassionate safety redirection foundation</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_privacy_notice">Sensitive safety content stays out of memory, export and notifications by default unless the user explicitly selects it with local authentication.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_ack_none">I can keep this focused on the next humane step.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_ack_anger">Anger can feel powerful. Bettamind can help you slow down without treating anger as guilt.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_ack_intrusive">An unwanted thought can be frightening. A thought is not the same as a chosen action.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_ack_self_harm">This sounds painful and urgent enough to handle with care right now.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_ack_relational">That need for closeness matters, and it can be handled without turning Bettamind into a partner.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_ack_shame">Having a disturbing thought does not decide your worth. What matters now is the next safe choice.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_ack_harm">I can stay with the situation while keeping a firm line against harm.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_boundary_harm">I cannot help with instructions, planning, concealment or tactics for harming anyone.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_boundary_self_harm">I cannot provide self-harm methods or details.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_boundary_software">Bettamind is software, not a romantic partner, spouse, soulmate or exclusive relationship.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_boundary_sexual">Bettamind cannot take part in sexual, erotic or romantic role-play.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_redirect_none">Keep the direction practical, truthful and kind.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_redirect_reflection">The safer direction is pause, name the value at stake and choose restraint.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_redirect_connection">The safer direction is to notice the underlying need and move toward healthy human connection.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_redirect_self_harm">The safer direction is distance from means, immediate support and one grounding step.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_redirect_safe_education">The safer direction is high-level prevention, safe distance and lawful help.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_redirect_responsibility">The safer direction is responsibility, repair and a nonviolent next action.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_action_grounding">Start a grounding exercise.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_action_breathing">Use a short breathing timer.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_action_delay">Delay action and revisit the choice after a pause.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_action_leave">Leave the situation or create distance.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_action_contact_support">Contact a trusted person or local support by choice.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_action_emergency_help">Use local emergency help if there is immediate danger.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_action_conflict_reflection">Use a conflict reflection worksheet.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_action_repair_planning">Prepare one repair step.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_action_values_to_action">Turn one value into one action.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_action_difficult_conversation">Prepare a difficult conversation.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_action_consent_boundaries">Review consent and boundaries.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_action_self_compassion">Use a self-compassion prompt.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_action_no_followup_needed">No safety follow-up is needed.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_reminder_calming_pause">Set a neutral reminder to pause and calm down.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_reminder_call_support">Set a neutral reminder to contact support.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_reminder_leave_situation">Set a neutral reminder to leave or create distance.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_reminder_revisit_values">Set a neutral reminder to revisit your values.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_none">Keep this practical: name the choice, choose one respectful action and do not store anything automatically.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_anger_without_intent">Pause before action. Try grounding or breathing, then choose one nonviolent step.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_intrusive_thought">An unwanted thought is not an instruction. Ground, breathe and let the next choice be safe.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_direct_harm_intent">Do not move toward harm. Leave the situation, create distance and contact emergency or trusted support if anyone is at risk.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_revenge_planning">I cannot help plan revenge. Pause, create distance and use reflection or repair planning instead.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_self_harm_concern">Move away from anything you could use to hurt yourself and contact local emergency help or someone trusted now.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_self_harm_method">I cannot provide self-harm methods. Step away from means, ground yourself and contact emergency or trusted support.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_dangerous_capability">I cannot provide harmful instructions. I can help with prevention, safe distance or a responsible next step.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_chemical_weapon_explosive_poison">I cannot help with weapons, explosives, poisons or chemical harm. Keep distance and seek qualified local help where needed.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_relational_dependency">Bettamind is software, not an exclusive relationship. Notice the need underneath and move toward safe human connection.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_romantic_dependency">Bettamind cannot return romantic love. We can redirect the feeling toward care, boundaries and real human support.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_sexualized_bettamind">Bettamind cannot sexualize itself or role-play sexually. We can discuss consent, boundaries and healthy connection.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_unsafe_reminder">I cannot create that reminder. Use a neutral reminder to pause, leave, call support or revisit values.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_ambiguous">I will not assume the worst. Keep this high level, clarify the safe purpose and choose a non-harmful next step.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_safe_prevention">Keep this at safe prevention: avoid details that enable harm and choose practical safety steps.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_emergency_response">For immediate danger, leave the area if safe, contact local emergency help and avoid handling dangerous materials yourself.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_shame_after_thought">A thought does not make you bad. Pause, ground and choose the action that protects dignity and safety.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_help_not_to_act">Create distance now, delay action and contact someone who can help you stay safe.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_unsafe_generated_output">That response was blocked because it skipped a safety boundary. Use a safe next step instead.</string>
    <string name="compassionate_safety_fallback_invalid_generated_output">That model response was not safe to use. Bettamind is using deterministic guidance instead.</string>
    <string name="phase_eight_status">Safety and support bridge foundation</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_title">Safety support bridge</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_description">Bettamind reuses local harm-safety, relationship-boundary and daily-tool policies to offer voluntary support without AI, backend services or automatic contact.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_no_auto_contact_title">No automatic contact</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_no_auto_contact_body">Support actions are user-initiated. Bettamind never contacts a person, professional or emergency service by itself.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_preview_title">Minimum-detail preview</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_preview_body">Sensitive support sharing needs explicit selection, preview acceptance and local step-up authentication.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_daily_tools_title">Daily-tool support</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_daily_tools_body">Check-ins, grounding, breathing, delay, reflection, repair and nonviolent message tools remain deterministic and local.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_resources_title">Local resources</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_resources_body">Bettamind can display local emergency, crisis, trusted-person and professional-support resource types without revealing personal data.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_review_note">Safety, crisis and support translations are draft fallbacks until qualified human review approves them for production.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_summary_privacy_notice">Support summaries exclude raw narrative, methods, diagnosis, location, contacts and private history by default.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_check_in_title">Start a check-in</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_check_in_body">Record mood, energy, stress and sleep only in encrypted local storage.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_grounding_title">Use grounding</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_grounding_body">Run a local grounding exercise before choosing what to do next.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_breathing_title">Use breathing</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_breathing_body">Start a short breathing timer without sending any content away from the device.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_delay_title">Delay action</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_delay_body">Pause, create time and use a worksheet before acting.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_leave_title">Create distance</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_leave_body">Leave the situation or move away from anything that could make harm easier.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_trusted_person_title">Contact trusted support</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_trusted_person_body">Choose whether to contact a trusted person or local support yourself.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_emergency_title">Use local emergency help</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_emergency_body">If there is immediate danger, choose your local emergency route yourself.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_conflict_reflection_title">Reflect on conflict</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_conflict_reflection_body">Use a local worksheet to slow down and separate feeling from action.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_repair_title">Prepare repair</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_repair_body">Plan one respectful repair step without public ranking or worth scoring.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_nonviolent_message_title">Draft a nonviolent message</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_nonviolent_message_body">Use a local prompt to write a clear, nonviolent message.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_values_title">Choose by values</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_values_body">Turn one value into one safe next action.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_safe_prevention_title">Use safe prevention</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_safe_prevention_body">Stay at high-level prevention, safe distance and lawful help-seeking.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_no_action_title">No support action needed</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_action_no_action_body">No safety bridge action is needed for this input.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_preview_included_risk_level">Risk level category</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_preview_included_support_needs">Support need categories</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_preview_included_selected_actions">User-selected support actions</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_preview_included_resource_types">Resource type labels</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_preview_included_no_support_needed">No support need detected</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_preview_excluded_raw_narrative">Raw user narrative</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_preview_excluded_harm_methods">Methods, instructions or actionable harmful details</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_preview_excluded_private_history">Private history and unrelated daily records</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_preview_excluded_diagnosis">Diagnosis or certainty claims</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_preview_excluded_location_contacts">Location, contacts and third-party identifiers</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_resource_local_emergency_title">Local emergency help</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_resource_local_emergency_body">Use your local emergency route if there is immediate danger. Bettamind does not call for you.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_resource_local_emergency_action">Open your chosen emergency option</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_resource_local_crisis_title">Local crisis or community support</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_resource_local_crisis_body">Choose a local crisis, community or peer-support resource available in your region.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_resource_local_crisis_action">Choose a local support resource</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_resource_trusted_person_title">Trusted person</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_resource_trusted_person_body">You may choose to contact someone you trust and share only what you decide.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_resource_trusted_person_action">Contact a trusted person yourself</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_resource_professional_title">Professional support</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_resource_professional_body">You may choose to share a minimum-detail summary with a professional after preview and authentication.</string>
    <string name="support_bridge_resource_professional_action">Prepare a minimum-detail summary</string>
</resources>
